<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>2013 &#8211; Stefan Sargent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/2013/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 06:06:54 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>LOVE Hz</title>
		<link>/2013/11/26/love-hz/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 06:06:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1623</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[This Is Not a Goodbye, My Darling, This Is a Thank You Remember your first GF or BF? Of course you do. Mine is Christina McWilliams, a vision of 16-year-old loveliness. She gives me her school pin. I give her &#8230; <a href="/2013/11/26/love-hz/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>This Is Not a Goodbye, My Darling, This Is a Thank You</h1>
<div id="content-area">
<div id="node-64568">
<div>
<p>Remember your first GF or BF? Of course you do. Mine is Christina McWilliams, a vision of 16-year-old loveliness. She gives me her school pin. I give her mine. We hold hands, kiss and cuddle. I’m taking it slowly and then, poof, it’s over. She wants her school pin back. I cry for a week. I’m through with girls.</p>
<p><strong>For the Love of Mike</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1636" style="width: 160px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-12.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1636" class="size-full wp-image-1636" title="12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-1" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-12.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="523" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1636" class="wp-caption-text">Altec 21B Condenser microphone</p></div>
<p>In 1956 I am working at Radio 2UE. We have a new Altec 21B condenser mic. While her Saarinen curves might break your heart, she is flat from 20 to 15,000 Hz—the perfect blend of form and function. I am in love.</p>
<p>Kicking and screaming, I am conscripted into National Service and taken away for military training. By chance, I see a classified ad for my Altec princess. On my day off, while my Air Force mates are pub crawling, I’m catching a bus to meet the seller, Bill Armstrong. I spend every penny I have buying her. She is my first professional equipment purchase.</p>
<p><em>When I come home at night, she will be waiting.</em></p>
<p><em>She’ll be the truest gal in all this world.</em></p>
<p><em>I’d rather have an Altec 21B to call my own,</em></p>
<p><em>Than a fickle-minded real live girl.</em></p>
<p><strong>There Will Be Blood</strong></p>
<p>My love sleeps under my pillow in the Air Force Nissen hut. My fellow conscripts think I’m weird.</p>
<p>One night they try to take her away. I lash out and break the ringleader’s nose. There’s a lot of blood. After that no one dares to touch her or me.</p>
<p><strong>Hey Presto</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1639" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-2-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1639" class="size-medium wp-image-1639 " title="12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-2-1" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-2-1-300x225.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="225" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1639" class="wp-caption-text">Presto !C recording head</p></div>
<p>Out of the Air Force, I buy a Presto 1C cutting head, turntable and lathe and build a mini Abbey Road in my mother’s laundry. I specialize in cutting copies of impossible-to-get LPs.</p>
<p>My biggest hit is <em>The Songs of Tom Lehrer</em>. Lehrer sings of drugs, sexual diseases and poisoning pigeons: all the things that make life worthwhile.</p>
<p><strong>Jazz Me Blues</strong></p>
<p>In 1959, the princess, my friend Robert Parker and I drive to the Cootamundra Jazz Convention. While Robert is recording the jazz using my Altec, I’m filming the event with a new Bolex H16.</p>
<p>A week later I marry wife #1. Big mistake. I should have stayed true to my princess.</p>
<p><strong>Eight Years Later</strong></p>
<p>Wife #1 is gone but I have my loyal techie family: Altec, Presto, Bolex, Éclair and Nagra.</p>
<div id="attachment_1641" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-3.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1641" class="size-full wp-image-1641" title="12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-3" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/12Learn-ProdDiary-LoveHz-3.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="800" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1641" class="wp-caption-text">Stefan and Tricia 1968</p></div>
<p>I make TV spots, pop videos and full-length documentaries. I haven’t dated a girl for six months.</p>
<p>Mike Pearce is a close friend. “Come on, Stefan, you’ve got to start taking girls out again.” Nope, it Hz.</p>
<p>“Snap out of it. Ask the next girl who comes to the door. You can do it.”</p>
<p>On cue, <em>knock knock</em>. I fling open the front door. “My darling! At last I’ve found you. I know I sound crazy but I’d like to ask you out.”</p>
<p><em>“Oh dear, no. I’m here to meet my daughter, Tricia. She wants some modeling work. You should ask her out.”</em></p>
<p><strong>Love Me, Love My Nagra</strong></p>
<p>Two months later, Tricia and I are in London. I’m shooting TV interviews, Tricia is recording the sound.</p>
<p>We meet Aussie friends. <em>“Have you got a sound studio? We want to record </em>The Bee Gees Story<em>.”</em> “No, but I can build one. I have a great microphone, an Altec 21B.”</p>
<p>Robert, Tricia and I build Molinare. Twelve years later we have 40,000 sq. ft. and 100+ employees, but my darling Altec has vanished, gone forever.</p>
<p>Princess, thank you: thank you for showing me that there would come a time when I could eventually let you go.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MISTAKES: I&#8217;VE MADE A FEW &#8211; OK, A LOT</title>
		<link>/2013/11/02/mistakes-ive-made-a-few-a-lot/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 15:32:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1603</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[How I love American Cinematographer magazine. Next to Digital Video, it’s my all-time favorite. Every month I open it to the inside back cover, the same as you do with Digital Video, but instead of my stuff, there’s an interview &#8230; <a href="/2013/11/02/mistakes-ive-made-a-few-a-lot/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<div id="pdate"><span style="font-size: 16px;">How I love </span><a style="font-size: 16px;" href="http://www.theasc.com/ac_magazine/October2013/current.php"><em>American Cinematographer</em></a><span style="font-size: 16px;"> magazine. Next to </span><em>Digital Video</em><span style="font-size: 16px;">, it’s my all-time favorite. Every month I open it to the inside back cover, the same as you do with </span><em>Digital Video</em><span style="font-size: 16px;">, but instead of my stuff, there’s an interview with a famous ASC cameraman.</span></div>
</div>
<div>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>And every month there’s the killer-diller question that stumps them all: <em>“Have you made any memorable blunders?”</em></p>
<p>Now if you were earning $XX,000 a day, would you admit to any wrongdoing? No, of course you wouldn’t.</p>
<p><strong>Don Burgess, ASC:</strong><em> “Blunders? Cinematographers don’t like that word, but we do like ‘happy accidents,’ which we take credit for all the time.”</em></p>
<p>Nice one, Don. Completely sidestepped the issue—should be a politician.</p>
<p><strong><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/11Learn-ProdDiary-Mistakes-1.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1611" title="11Learn-ProdDiary-Mistakes-1" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/11Learn-ProdDiary-Mistakes-1.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="180" /></a>Darius Khondji, ASC</strong>: <em>“Many, many blunders.”</em></p>
<p>That’s it? Just three words? Come on, tell us some mistakes you made on <em>Midnight in Paris</em> or <em>Se7en</em>. Please, we really want to know&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>Dante Spinotti, ASC:</strong> “<em>Thirty years ago I was shooting 16mm reversal and pushing to 2000 ASA. Later, all I could see in the shot were the torches the actors were holding.”</em></p>
<p>Well, I guess it was a mistake—but 30 years ago. Tell us a blunder on <em>X-Men</em> or <em>L.A. Confidential.</em> Something recent&#8230;</p>
<table style="height: 327px;" border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" width="245" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>And on and on they go with pathetic, trivial mistakes:</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><em>I accidentally turned on a smoke machine&#8230;</em></p>
<p><em>I played the piano in front of&#8230;</em></p>
<p><em>I put the film in the wrong way round when I was a clapper-loader 40 years ago&#8230;</em></p>
<p><strong>Now It’s My Turn</strong></p>
<p>It’s 1975. I’m hired to go to Portugal, where SuperSer butane heaters are made. <a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/superser2.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-full wp-image-1619" title="superser" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/superser2.jpg" alt="" width="150" height="225" /></a>I shoot their factory, the draftsmen, the cargo ship being loaded, and somehow, don’t ask me how, the SuperSer rep and I wind up on a Portuguese beach. I shoot the beach, the sunbathers—nice atmospheric stuff. We have a beer and enjoy the view.</p>
<p>I reload an Éclair 16mm magazine on top of an upturned boat, change magazines and—wait for it—leave the can of precious film on the upturned boat.</p>
<p>We fly back to London. <em>Quelle horreur</em>—there’s a can missing. Of course it would be the 400 ft. can that has all the really important shots.<a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/ipanema_girl.jpg-1.png"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-1616" title="ipanema_girl.jpg" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/ipanema_girl.jpg-1.png" alt="" width="200" height="310" /></a></p>
<p>My U.K. client speaks Portuguese and phones the police station nearest the beach. Wonder of wonders, it’s been handed in. The police overnight the film can back to London and it’s all there, unopened, intact, perfect.</p>
<p><strong>It Was Only Last Week</strong></p>
<p>None of this <em>“when I was an assistant 40 years ago.”</em></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>iPhone shoot</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>My good friend Dennis is doing a shoot. He wants me to cover reverse angles. I’d do anything for Dennis since my cat bit and peed all over him. So I turn up with not one camera but three.</p>
<p>And, would you believe it, all three die, one after the other. The GoPro runs for a while, powered by a USB supply, then locks up, stone-cold dead.</p>
<p>Camera two: I thought it had a 64 GB chip; nope, it’s a partially full 16 GB chip. One hundred percent full and dead after just 30 minutes.</p>
<p>The camera I’m operating has a battery that says <em>4.5 hours</em>. It lies. Dead before two hours. I go to get another battery and the hotel staff has kindly put my camera case into Lost and Found &#8230; and the guy with the key is away at lunch.</p>
<p>A camera! A camera! My kingdom for a camera. Hey, I’ve got an iPhone. <a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/11Learn-ProdDiary-Mistakes-4.jpg"><img class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-1621" title="11Learn-ProdDiary-Mistakes-4" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/11Learn-ProdDiary-Mistakes-4-300x214.jpg" alt="" width="300" height="214" /></a>I balance it on the tripod and shoot. I feel pretty stupid but it works.</p>
<p><strong>Have You Made Any Memorable Blunders?</strong></p>
<p>Yes, many, many.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DRONUS INTERRUPTUS</title>
		<link>/2013/09/27/dronus-interruptus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2013 02:21:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1589</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Job That Flew Away You remember Mary from my Production Diary a couple of months ago. Yes, of course you do: she’s the client who said, “It’s perfect. I absolutely love it!” and then, a few weeks later, wanted &#8230; <a href="/2013/09/27/dronus-interruptus/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>The Job That Flew Away</h1>
<div id="content-area">
<div id="node-63987">
<div>
<div id="pdate"><span style="font-size: 16px;">You remember Mary from my </span><a style="font-size: 16px;" href="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/dv/feature/production-diary-ch-ch-ch-ch-changes-turn-and-face-strain/62485">Production Diary</a><span style="font-size: 16px;"> a couple of months ago. Yes, of course you do: she’s the client who said, </span><em>“It’s perfect. I absolutely love it!”</em><span style="font-size: 16px;"> and then, a few weeks later, wanted a dumb title at the start.</span></div>
</div>
<div>
<p>Now she’s got another job for me and it’s brilliant. All is forgiven. A guest lodge in the Sierra Nevada mountains: spectacular scenery, hiking trails, horse riding, hot springs, tall red fir trees, snow-topped mountains <em>and</em> a decent-sized budget to boot. In short, a perfect subject for me and my <a href="http://www.dji.com/product/phantom/">Phantom Quadcopter.</a></p>
<p>I bill her for 50 percent up front. She pays quickly. I’m rich. Time to upgrade my Phantom.</p>
<p><strong>Did Gyre and Gimble in the Wabe</strong></p>
<p>I want a <a href="http://www.dji.com/product/zenmuse-h3-2d-gimbal/">DJI Zenmuse H3-2D</a> gimbal for my Phantom. The demo video is a knockout.</p>
<p><iframe src="//player.vimeo.com/video/62966103" width="600" height="350" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe> </p>
<p><a href="http://vimeo.com/62966103">First test of the Zenmuse for GoPro</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/iflydji">DJI Innovations</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com/">Vimeo</a>.</p

I pack my Phantom and mail to Florida for gimbal installation. It comes back with strange black wires hanging out of its clamshell body—no instructions, just a heap of bits and pieces. Even the GoPro is loose.


<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/10Learn-ProdDiary-Dronus-2.JPG" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Inside the Phantom with Zenmuse gimbal board and Naza power management unit</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>After a full day, we crack it. If the Phantom wobbles, the gimbal keeps the <a href="http://gopro.com/cameras/hd-hero3-black-edition">GoPro HERO3</a> dead stable. Pure magic.</p>
<p><strong>First-Person View</strong></p>
<p>We in the RC biz call it FPV. <em>“Got FPV?”</em>“You bet, it’s an RC Logger.” Jargon for saying you’re transmitting air-to-ground video from your GoPro.</p>
<p>The GoPro’s video signal comes out of the Zenmuse board packed way inside the Phantom. Undo 16 screws and find the board. Plug in the video out wire and push it through a hole in the Phantom shell. Do up 16 screws.</p>
<p>Now I need 5 volts for the FPV transmitter. Gulp. Undo 16 screws. Cut ’n solder. Do up 16 screws. It doesn’t work. So 16 out—rewire—15 back. Where’s that missing screw?</p>
<p>Geronimo, I have FPV. But the idgy-widgy monitor is impossible to see in daylight. Nothing but the best for Mary; I lash out more of my 50 percent upfront and buy an OLED 7.7” monitor and sunshade.</p>
<p><strong>There’s Something About Mary</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/10Learn-ProdDiary-Dronus-3.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Zenmuse gimbal holding the GoPro HERO3—FPV transmitter mounted with Velcro</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>And that <em>something</em> is called Jane. Mary has given her the job of producing me.</p>
<p>I need a producer like a hole in the head.</p>
<p>Now the e-mails start flowing. Jane wants a script, a shot list, a budget—all the usual film school crap. She drones on and on, excuse the pun.</p>
<p>Then suddenly it’s off. Bad weather. Delayed for two months. Hey, it rained for a day. Two months! Summer will be over.</p>
<p><strong>My Beamish Boy</strong></p>
<p>While I’m waiting, I discover Sam. He flies my Phantom like a real pro; sheer artistry to watch. I hire Sam and his brother, Jack, to help me with the shoot. Mary will be pleased.<a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/sam-and-jack-phantom.jpg"><img class="alignright size-large wp-image-1591" title="sam and jack phantom" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/sam-and-jack-phantom-1024x682.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="426" /></a></p>
<p>Then another e-mail from Jane, ONE DAY BEFORE THE SHOOT …</p>
<p><strong>Phantom of the Off Now</strong></p>
<p><em>Stephan </em>(she can’t even get my name right!)<em>, would you absolutely kill me if we needed to reschedule the shoot? I am terribly ill with a nasty flu and just not getting better. I might rally but wanted to take your temperature regarding a possible switch to September or June of next season—2014.</em></p>
<p>Sam, Jack and I are packed, ready to go—and she pulls the plug. Zap!</p>
<p>Bitter? No, just sad. I really wanted that job.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DO YOU BELIEVE IN MIRACLES?</title>
		<link>/2013/09/11/do-you-believe-in-miracles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2013 20:16:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With Me, They Happen All the Time Miracle at the BBC I am making a VidiWall about the first 50 years of British television. I am in the office of the head of the BBC’s library. It’s 1986 and I &#8230; <a href="/2013/09/11/do-you-believe-in-miracles/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>With Me, They Happen All the Time</h1>
<div id="content-area">
<div id="node-63674">
<div>
<p><strong>Miracle at the BBC</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/09Learn-ProdDiary-Miracles-BBC_the%20wars_of_the_roses.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I am making a VidiWall about the first 50 years of British television. I am in the office of the head of the BBC’s library.</p>
<p>It’s 1986 and I say, “I used to work at BBC Ealing Studios in 1965. I edited<em>The</em> <em>Wars of the Roses.”</em></p>
<p>She replies, “Oh yes, I know that program. The film cans would be downstairs with ten million films and tapes.”</p>
<p>We go down to the vaults. It’s vast; row after row of racks stretching into infinity. Our librarian leads us to the royal vault, a locked cage. “This is where all the films about the royal family are stored.”</p>
<p>She turns and looks at me and goes white. <em>“Where did you get that from?”</em> I look down. I’m holding a 35mm film can labeled <em>The Wars of the Roses—Part 1</em>. I have no recollection of picking it up. Now it’s my colleague Bob Auger’s turn. <em>“That’s impossible,”</em> and he too goes into shock. I’m the only one looking normal. “My party trick,” I jest.</p>
<p>Friends, this is 100 percent true. Out of 10 million films and videotapes, I wind up with my 21-year-old film can mysteriously in my hand.</p>
<p><strong>Strangers on A Train</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/09Learn-ProdDiary-Miracles-french%20couchette.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I’m on a train from Calais to Toulon. It’s a couchette carriage, meaning that the seats are also bed bunks—four to each compartment. Normally there are couchettes for guys and separate ones for ladies. Someone has screwed up and I’m with two middle-aged ladies. They tell me to stay.</p>
<p>The older woman is an actress, Jean Anderson; she is in a BBC TV series,<em>Tenko</em>, and going to Le Lavandou to stay with her friend Betty Franks. “I know Betty.” The other lady is surprised that I should know the person she’s staying with.</p>
<p>She is a dignified, well spoken lady. <em>“You wouldn’t know any of my friends or contacts.”</em> “Let me guess: you live in London, in Hampstead.” <em>“You saw my passport.”</em> “No, of course not. I just guessed.” <em>“Good guess, but where in Hampstead?”</em> Hmmm—it’s like picking a street name in San Jose or Boise or Culver City.</p>
<p>We lived in Gayton Road, Hampstead, so I say, “You live in Gayton Road.” OMG, now she’s turning pale and fidgeting. <em>“What number?”</em> We lived in 56. Our next door neighbor rents out his basement apartment. “You live in 58 Gayton Road.”</p>
<p>Bulls eye!</p>
<p>Next time you’re in a train or on a plane, try guessing where the person sitting next to you lives. You know that’s impossible, but I did it.</p>
<p><strong><em>Le Chien Miracle</em></strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/09Learn-ProdDiary-Miracles-radar%20le%20chien%20miracle.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I’m in France shooting for Esso. I’ve written a script where a dog lies down in front of a car. The driver tries to reverse out but the dog runs round to the back of the car.</p>
<p>It’s a five-day shoot. My French Esso client keeps asking me, <em>“Stefan, </em>mon ami<em>, when are we doing the dog scene?”</em> I tell him that it was a silly idea. Nope, he wants the dog.</p>
<p>Now it’s the last day of the shoot.<em>“Stefan, you naughty man, the dog scene, </em>s’il te plaît<em>?”</em> We are in a nondescript suburb—lawns, houses, trees. I look across the road and there in the distance is a man walking a dog. I run over.</p>
<p><em>“Excusé-moi, je fais un film…” “I speak English, what do you want?”</em> “I’m making a little film over there, I need a dog for a shot.” <em>“But how did you know we were here? This is Radar, the Wonder Dog. We have a show on French television: </em>Radar, Le Chien Miracle<em>.”</em></p>
<p>That’s three miracles. I have more …</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>THE SHINY BLACK DOOR</title>
		<link>/2013/08/21/the-shiny-black-door/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2013 04:25:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When New Technology Was Banned I cross the park in Soho Square, go to number 2 and press the buzzer. It’s 1964 and I’ve just arrived from Australia. Eventually the lock on the shiny black door clicks open and I &#8230; <a href="/2013/08/21/the-shiny-black-door/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>When New Technology Was Banned</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1582" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/640px-SohoSquare1992.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1582" class="size-full wp-image-1582" title="640px-SohoSquare1992" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/640px-SohoSquare1992.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="411" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1582" class="wp-caption-text">Soho Square, London</p></div>
<p>I cross the park in Soho Square, go to number 2 and press the buzzer. It’s 1964 and I’ve just arrived from Australia.</p>
<p>Eventually the lock on the shiny black door clicks open and I walk down the hall to a small sliding window. I am inside the all-powerful ACTT union headquarters. (ACTT is the Association of Cinematograph Television and Allied Technicians, a trade union in the United Kingdom.)</p>
<p>“Hello, I wrote to you from Sydney. I’d like to join the union.” The lady behind the window smiles. She tells me that the only way to join is to have a job—“but you can’t get a job without a union card.” The window slides closed.</p>
<p>A week later I have an interview with the chief executive of ITN. He’s a New Zealander, I’m Australian. It helps. We watch a short film of mine. “Terrific! I’ll take you on. Make friends and you’ll get into the union. No worries.”</p>
<p>He’s wrong. Despite my constant trips to the shiny black door with free tickets to Wimbledon and Lords, I never get into the union. Finally, phone calls are made; I leave ITN and start the next day at the BBC.</p>
<p><strong>Molinare Sound</strong></p>
<p>Now it’s 1975, I have four successful sound studios called Molinare. We have a great staff and I’m free to continue as a filmmaker.</p>
<p>One of my clients is Redifon Flight Simulation. They send me to Salt Lake City to film the very first CGI simulator. The month before, Compact Video, an L.A. company, had failed in shooting the simulator using video equipment. I shoot using high-speed film and then fly to L.A. to visit Compact.</p>
<p><strong>Small but Perfectly Formed</strong></p>
<p>Compact Video is a revelation. While London companies are using giant three-lens cameras, Compact has lightweight shoulder-mounted Norelco PCP-90s and small battery-powered recorders.</p>
<div id="attachment_1577" style="width: 679px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1577" class="size-full wp-image-1577" title="08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-1" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-1.jpg" alt="" width="669" height="480" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-1.jpg 669w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-1-300x215.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 669px) 100vw, 669px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1577" class="wp-caption-text">Compact Video’s Norelco PCP90 camera</p></div>
<div id="attachment_1578" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1578" class="size-full wp-image-1578" title="08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-2" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-2.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="443" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-2.jpg 800w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-2-300x166.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-2-768x425.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1578" class="wp-caption-text">Compact Video’s 2” Ampex VR3000 portable recorder</p></div>
<p>I return to London determined to build a Compact look-alike using the latest technology.</p>
<p><strong>The Ah-Ha Experience</strong></p>
<p>It’s September 1976, I’m at IBC, the European NAB. On display is the Ampex VPR-1 1” video recorder. OMG—I fall in love and order three machines.</p>
<p>Tricia finds bigger premises, much bigger: 40,000 sq. ft. We build a studio and a 1” edit suite, the first outside the States.</p>
<p><strong>Black Is Black</strong></p>
<p>An engineer from a competitor comes to see me. “Last night there was a meeting of shop stewards, and Molinare has been declared black. The main reason is you are using new technology that hasn’t been approved by the ACTT union. Commercial TV stations have been told not to play out any tape from Molinare.”</p>
<p>“Restrictive trade practices,” says my attorney and we both go off to see Alan Sapper, general secretary of the union.</p>
<p><strong>Right Back Where We Started From</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1579" style="width: 690px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-3.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1579" class="size-full wp-image-1579" title="08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-3" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-3.jpg" alt="" width="680" height="448" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-3.jpg 680w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/08/08Learn-ProdDiary-ShinyBlackDoor-3-300x198.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 680px) 100vw, 680px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1579" class="wp-caption-text">1978 Ampex 1” recorders at Molinare—banned by the British television union</p></div>
<p>So here we are again, 13 years later, at number two’s shiny black door.</p>
<p>I tell Sapper that if I can’t use my 1” machines, Molinare will go bust. I have no option but to sue them.</p>
<p>The mood turns icy. “Nobody but nobody sues a union, especially this one. If you do this, Stefan, I promise you that you’ll never work in this industry again.”</p>
<p><strong>Showtime</strong></p>
<p>Inside the Law Courts, the barristers stand and make their cases. Then a surprise: Sapper calls his barrister aside. The ACTT will meet all Molinare demands. The new 1” technology is approved.</p>
<p>Outside, Sapper greets me like an old friend. “We never thought you’d have the nerve to go all the way. No hard feelings&#8230;.” I force a smile and shake hands. “So I can still work in the business?”</p>
<p><strong>A Picnic in the Park</strong></p>
<p>Sitting on the grass outside 2 Soho Square, we eat a picnic lunch, pop champagne and toast the shiny black door. Bliss&#8230;.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SEARCHING FOR SILVERMAN</title>
		<link>/2013/06/26/searching-for-silverma/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2013 18:32:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1548</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Cat Stays in the Picture” It’s Friday morning and the phone is ringing. “Howard here. I need a 10-minute video about my new product. Can you do it?” “Sure, how about 10 tomorrow. I’ll shoot it greenscreen.” Greenscreen is &#8230; <a href="/2013/06/26/searching-for-silverma/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong><em>The Cat Stays in the Picture”<br />
</em></strong><br />
It’s Friday morning and the phone is ringing.</p>
<p><em>“Howard here. I need a 10-minute video about my new product. Can you do it?”</em></p>
<p>“Sure, how about 10 tomorrow. I’ll shoot it greenscreen.”</p>
<p>Greenscreen is a quick fix. If I’m an expert in anything, it’s fast, painless greenscreen.</p>
<p>We do it in our living room. From normal domestic family room to greenscreen deluxe studio—voilà, 15 minutes flat!</p>
<p>The <a href="http://www.lowel.com/kits_rifa.html">Lowel Rifa</a> light goes here, the chair and mic here. The <a href="http://www.dedolight.com/www/dedolight/default.php?la=0">Dedolight</a> greenscreen light right behind the speaker; the greenscreen itself, at the back of the room. I’ll add a touch of Dedo backlight on hair or skimming the dark side of the face.</p>
<p><strong>Softgels</strong></p>
<p>Howard arrives. He wants a teleprompter. “No, you’ll be fine. Sit down. Tell us about these softgels.” We shoot for a while and then I say, “You’ve warmed up so much, let’s do it all again from the top.”</p>
<p><em>“Hello, I’m Howard Silverman. I’m 86. About 40 years ago I was diagnosed with cancer. I went to see Dr. Patel in Edmonton, Alberta. He told me, ‘You don’t have cancer, you have kidney failure.’ He treated and cured me.</em></p>
<p><em>Recently I decided to visit him again. He put me on TZI RU Softgels. After three days, I woke up in the middle of the night with a massive erection. 86 years old and I have an erection, isn’t that amazing!”</em></p>
<p>Howard talks for another 10 minutes, but you’ve got the gist. As he leaves, he says, <em>“Add some shots illustrating what I say; just search the internet.”</em></p>
<p>The door closes. I race to<a href="http://istockphoto.com/"> istockphoto.com</a>. Search for <em>erection</em>: the Eiffel Tower, the Leaning Tower of Pisa, how about reverse motion of a chimney demolition?</p>
<p><strong>Keep It Real</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1553" style="width: 779px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/rob-parker.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1553" class="size-full wp-image-1553" title="rob-parker" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/rob-parker.jpg" alt="" width="769" height="432" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/rob-parker.jpg 854w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/rob-parker-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/rob-parker-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 769px) 100vw, 769px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1553" class="wp-caption-text">Robert Parker</p></div>
<p>Greenscreen is, of course, a cheap trick. The best way to do a head-and-shoulders interview is right there on location.</p>
<p>My friend Robert Parker wants a video about how he restores jazz records.</p>
<p>I shoot him in his studio in Devon; just a single bounce light.</p>
<p><strong>On Location</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1554" style="width: 730px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/jamie-kutch.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1554" class="size-full wp-image-1554 " title="jamie-kutch" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/jamie-kutch.jpg" alt="" width="720" height="307" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/jamie-kutch.jpg 900w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/jamie-kutch-300x128.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/jamie-kutch-768x328.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 720px) 100vw, 720px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1554" class="wp-caption-text">Jamie Kutch</p></div>
<p>For my pinot documentary, I need winemaker Jamie Kutch talking about the joys and disappointments of the harvest. Can you imagine doing that greenscreen? Of course not.</p>
<p>Here I am with Jamie, both buried deep in grapevine. Isn’t backlight wonderful?</p>
<p><strong>I Shoot My Wife</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1555" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/tricia-rose.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1555" class="size-large wp-image-1555" title="tricia-rose" src="https://prior.stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/tricia-rose-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="360" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2013/06/tricia-rose-1024x576.jpg 1024w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/tricia-rose-300x169.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/tricia-rose-768x432.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2013/06/tricia-rose.jpg 1600w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1555" class="wp-caption-text">Tricia Rose</p></div>
<p>Tricia has an online business making and selling linen bedding. She needs a video. I’m torn between filming her sewing and looking up to camera or the old greenscreen trick. I give in. We’ll do it greenscreen.</p>
<p>My friend John interviews her for half an hour. Overwhelmed by all the footage, I put it away. Finally, “I’ve got to finish that stupid linen video.”</p>
<p>At this stage, all I have is greenscreen. We set up a table for the background. Add a sewing machine and a basket full of linen. Out of nowhere, our Himalayan cat Shibui jumps up on the table and starts parading back and forward. How does she know? If she had a garter, guys would be tucking in $20 bills.</p>
<p>Editing the video is going to be fun. I chop Tricia’s 30-minute interview down to three and add the best of Shibui’s cat walk as a background. An hour later, it’s done.</p>
<p>We show the result to friends and family. “The cat’s overacting.” “Distracting. Her eyes are too big.” “Cut out the cat!”</p>
<p>Oh no—<em>the cat stays in the picture! </em>See it here:<br />
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/rXpVABq5qfI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
<p>BTW, please don’t contact me for TZI RU Softgels. The FDA is testing them. Apparently, they can’t get enough.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>MY CLAIM TO FLAME</title>
		<link>/2013/06/09/production-diary-my-claim-to-flame/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 23:32:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1539</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Best of My Stuff His name is Chuck. At the NAB Show, he sees my name tag. “Wait ’til I tell my wife that I met you. We loooove your stuff. Our favorite story is ‘Dead in Denver.’” “Thanks,but &#8230; <a href="/2013/06/09/production-diary-my-claim-to-flame/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>The Best of My Stuff</h1>
<div id="content-area">
<div id="node-62811">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<p>His name is Chuck. At the NAB Show, he sees my name tag.</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><em>“Wait ’til I tell my wife that I met you. We loooove your stuff. Our favorite story is ‘Dead in Denver.’”</em></p>
<p>“Thanks,but I didn’t write that. Perhaps you mean ‘Death of A Filmmaker?’”</p>
<p><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/06Learn-ProdDiary-ClaimFlame-1.gif" alt="" /></p>
<p><em>“No, you’re dead in Denver. I’m sure. It’s our all-time favorite. Do you have a favorite?”</em></p>
<p>“Let’s find a place to sit down and I’ll tell you my favorite&#8230;”</p>
<p><strong>Clickerty Clack</strong></p>
<p>It’s 1976, we’re on an early train to Port Talbot, Wales, where British Steel has its enormous steelworks.</p>
<p>I’m making a 25-minute corporate film for Acrow Engineering with the catchy title, “The Steel Stockholder’s Strongest Supporter.”</p>
<p>I need an opening sequence. It’s a 15-second shot of Michael Barratt, a well known TV presenter, standing in front of a cauldron pouring molten steel. He’ll say something like, “This is where it all starts&#8230;”</p>
<p>Who needs a tripod? Not me. I can shoulder-hold without a quiver. Who needs lights? Not us. Hey, there will be plenty of factory lights. So, no lights.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/06Learn-ProdDiary-ClaimFlame-2.jpg" alt="" />I have a small Éclair ACL 16mm camera with one fixed 12mm lens, just fine for to-camera pieces. Tricia has a Sony ECM77 lavalier mic and a tiny Nagra SN recorder.</p>
<p><strong>Tea and Biscuits</strong></p>
<p>We taxi from the railway station. Michael has driven there and we meet up in the British Steel PR office. The PR man is delighted to chat with a celebrity like Michael. We have morning tea. <em>“When is the crew going to arrive?”</em></p>
<p>“We’re all here,” I reply.</p>
<p><em>“Where’s your equipment?”</em></p>
<p>“Here’s the camera and Tricia has the tape recorder in her pocket.”</p>
<p><em>“But you will need lights. Last week we had the BBC here and they had three trucks with lights and generators. It’s dark in there.”</em></p>
<p><strong>Be Afraid, Be Very Afraid</strong></p>
<p>He takes us inside the foundry and he’s right; just pitch blackness. I have screwed up.</p>
<p>I find a good spot for Michael where I can see the steel being poured. His face is in silhouette. I am panicking. The PR man senses my pain and smiles. I hate him.</p>
<p>I see a collection of cardboard boxes, even a newspaper. The guardian angel of filmmakers is with me.</p>
<p>I stack up the boxes between Michael and the camera. Tricia runs the tape recorder. I watch the cauldron as it moves into place.</p>
<p><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/06Learn-ProdDiary-ClaimFlame-3.jpg" alt="" /></p>
<p>I borrow a lighter from the PR man. Light the newspaper. It catches fire. The boxes start to burn. The cauldron is about to tip, molten iron about to pour. Roll film.</p>
<p>“Action, Michael.”</p>
<p><strong>Flames Are Growing Higher</strong></p>
<p><em>“Here at British Steel is where our story starts.”</em> Michael is now behind a wall of fire. The distant cauldron is pouring. Sparks are flying. <em>“The molten steel behind me will find its way into the buildings and bridges of tomorrow.”</em> The flames get lower. His face is lit by a red flicker. <em>“But will this precious asset be stored properly or will it be left to rust on the ground?”</em> Crump. The boxes collapse. The fire dies out.</p>
<p>“I’ve never seen anything like that in my life,” gasps the British Steel man.</p>
<p>On the return trip to London, the three of us are killing ourselves with laughter.</p>
<p>“If this doesn’t come out, we can never go back.”</p>
<p><strong>Firelight Becomes You</strong></p>
<p>The film comes back from the lab and it’s perfect. The flames and firelight are amazing; who needs three lighting trucks?</p>
<p>Michael tells everyone. My exploits go viral. In ’76, I’m known as the guy who lit the fire at British Steel.</p>
<p>**********</p>
<p>“That, Chuck, is the best of my stuff.”</p>
<p>“Wow, great story. You were so cool. How did you lose it?”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BLACK IS BLACK, I WANT MY FACILITY BACK</title>
		<link>/2013/05/25/black-is-black-i-want-my-facility-back/</link>
					<comments>/2013/05/25/black-is-black-i-want-my-facility-back/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2013 00:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Full Length Articles]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1537</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LONDON – GROUND ZERO I cross the park in Soho Square, go up to a black shiny door at number two and press the buzzer. It’s 1964 and I’ve just arrived from Australia. Eventually the lock on the door clicks &#8230; <a href="/2013/05/25/black-is-black-i-want-my-facility-back/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>LONDON – GROUND ZERO</strong></p>
<p>I cross the park in Soho Square, go up to a black shiny door at number two and press the buzzer. It’s 1964 and I’ve just arrived from Australia.</p>
<p>Eventually the lock on the door clicks open and I walk down the hall to a small sliding window. I am inside the all-powerful ACTT union headquarters.</p>
<p><em>“Hello, my name is Stefan Sargent. I wrote to you from Sydney. I’d like to join the union.”</em> The lady behind the window smiles. She tells me that the only way to join is to have a job – “but, of course, you can’t get a job without a union card.” The window slides closed.</p>
<p>A week later, I have an interview with the Chief Executive of ITN, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geoffrey_Cox_(journalist)">Geoffrey Cox</a>. He’s a New Zealander, I’m Australian. It helps. We watch a short film of mine. “Terrific! I’ll take you on. Make friends and you’ll get into the union. No worries.”</p>
<p><strong>COLOUR ME BLACK</strong></p>
<p>My first day at ITN, I’m in the cameraman’s room. “Who are you?” <em>“I’m the new cameraman.”</em> “Not bloody likely!”</p>
<p>He goes to the door and stops anyone else from entering. Bemused, I get up to go and talk to him. Now it’s his, and the other cameramen’s, turn to enter the room. I walk from the door back inside, they all get up and walk out.</p>
<p>I am declared black. No one will work with me. They won’t even talk to me. Until one day, sitting in the secretaries’ office, an ITN cameraman walks in.</p>
<p><strong>DON’T GO DOWN IN THE TUBE TODAY</strong></p>
<p>“Would you like to go on a shoot with us?” I gratefully accept. We go down into the depths of the work-in-progress Victoria line. It’s an underground building site with workers drilling into the rock. We walk into a new deserted tunnel. My colleagues have torches. Then without saying a word, they suddenly vanish. I’m alone in the dark. It’s pitch black. I grope my way back along the rough walls. I know it’s time to quit.</p>
<p>The ITN management makes some phone calls and a week later I’m employed at BBC Ealing Studios. I seek out the ACTT rep., <em>“I’d like to join the union.”</em> “Great, we need more members. There’s a meeting this weekend. Please join us.”</p>
<p>I’m in. No longer black, I am a card-carrying member of the ACTT.</p>
<p><strong>MOLINARE SOUND STUDIOS</strong></p>
<p>Now it’s 1975, I have four successful sound studios in Broadwick Street, Soho, called Molinare. We have a great staff and I’m free to continue as a filmmaker.</p>
<p>One of my clients is Redifon Flight Simulation. The pilot in the simulator cockpit sees the outside world from a television camera moving over a large model landscape. I decide the best way to capture it is to put blue card on the cockpit windows, give the pilot a small monitor and shoot on video. I need an OB truck and book Trilion. In their Soho machine room, we chromakey it all together. The video scene in the simulator windows is sharp and clear. My client is delighted. I’m now an expert in video production.</p>
<p>Redifon invests in Evans &amp; Sutherland, a high tech computer graphics company in Salt Lake City, Utah. Following my Trilion example, E &amp; S book an OB truck from Burbank based, Compact Video. The shoot is a disaster. Compact’s cameras cannot record the projected picture.</p>
<p>As the reigning expert, I am flown to Utah. I ask the simulator pilot to take half an hour to land the plane and run my modified Éclair film camera at 4 frames a second. My hope is that the six times longer exposure will capture the faint projected images.</p>
<p>While the 16mm film is being processed in New York, I visit Compact in Burbank.</p>
<p><strong>SMALL AND PERFECTLY FORMED</strong></p>
<p>Compact Video is a revelation.</p>
<p>While Trilion in London is using giant, three lens cameras, Compact has lightweight shoulder mounted Norelco PCP-90s – not much heavier than my own 16mm Éclair.</p>
<p>While Trilion has tank sized 2” quad recorders in their OB truck, Compact has small battery powered Ampex VR-3000s.</p>
<p>And while Trilion’s editing facility is just two engineers in a machine room, Compact’s edit suite is Californian redwood walls, Eames chairs, and plush leather seating. The sliding doors on the left conceal the noise of their 2” quad machines. The sliding doors on the right, lead to a restaurant kitchen.</p>
<p>I return to London determined to build a Compact Video look-alike in Soho and immediately start looking for premises.</p>
<p>My wife, Tricia, tells me she’s found an empty building in Foubert’s Place that would make an ideal audio video complex. There’s no FOR SALE sign but we track down the Peachey Property Company. Peachey quotes £2 a sq. ft. for the school building but says if we take the adjacent building as well, they’ll drop the rent to £1 and lock into that rate in for five years. We take it all at just £1 a sq. ft..</p>
<p><strong>SETEMBER 21, 1976</strong></p>
<p>By chance, in Upper Regent Street, I see a sign, INTERNATIONAL BROADCASTING CONVENTION. I go down the stairs. The first exhibit is Ampex. On display is their new video recorder, the 1” VPR-1A.</p>
<p>It’s a friendly 1” tape recorder that is totally unlike the big 2” machines. Stop the tape – there’s a freeze frame – hand-turn the reel – watch one frame after the other. It’s just like editing film. I spend an hour playing. I’m in love. On impulse, I order three £40,000 machines from salesman, Ron Atkinson.</p>
<p>That afternoon, I’m back at Molinare, 43 Broadwick Street. “Where’s Tricia?”</p>
<p>Late that night our daughter is born.</p>
<p><strong>THE TECHNOLOGY REVOLUTION</strong></p>
<p>At a stroke, Compact Video is out of date.  So are Trilion, The Moving Picture Company, TVi, Goldcrest, Keith Ewart and ITN Facilities. Their 2” quad recorders all obsolete;  1” helical tape is the way to go.<strong> </strong></p>
<p>I phone Ron at Ampex. <em>“What’s happening?”</em> “Sorry, I don’t recognize your name. Stefan Sargent? Molinare? Oh yes, now, I remember …I thought you were joking. Three machines! You’re really serious!”</p>
<p>At the time, I have no idea that mine is Ampex’s only VPR-1A order.</p>
<p>Our builder, Alan Stewart, agrees to work on a “pay me when you can” basis. Little by little, we move our sound studios out of Broadwick Street to Foubert’s Place. I hire video engineers and video editors and, with great excitement, drive to Ampex in Reading to collect my machines.</p>
<p><strong>BLACK IS BLACK</strong></p>
<p>One day, an engineer from Trilion comes to see me. “Bad news, last night there was a meeting of shop stewards from the union approved facilities companies and Molinare has been declared black. The main reason is you are using new technology that hasn’t been approved by the ACTT.” He gives me the minutes of the meeting. ITV stations have been told not to play out any tape from Molinare. I’m shocked.</p>
<p>I contact Roy Lockett at ACTT HQ. “Sorry Stefan, you’ve lucked out. Your 1” technology is black. Make what you like, the ITV stations won’t play it.”</p>
<p>Tricia, had graduated from Sydney university with barrister <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Geoffrey_Robertson">Geoffrey Robertson</a>. Geoffrey made a name for himself in the 1971 Oz obscenity trial. He thinks we should have a left wing solicitor to represent us and suggests David Offenbach. It is a good choice. David is sympathetic to trade unions and knows labour laws.</p>
<p>I show David the letter to ITV stations declaring Molinare black. He feels we have a legitimate case of restrictive trade practices and we both go off to see <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Sapper">Alan Sapper</a>, General Secretary of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Association_of_Cinematograph_Television_and_Allied_Technicians">the</a> ACTT.</p>
<p><strong>RIGHT BACK WHERE WE STARTED FROM</strong></p>
<p>So here we are again at 2 Soho Square’s black shiny door, except it’s 13 years later. The meeting is cordial with Sapper telling me that I should have consulted the union before daring to buy “new technology”. I explain that if can’t use my video facilities, Molinare will probably go bust and that I have no option but to sue the union.</p>
<p>The mood turns icy. “Nobody but nobody sues a union, especially this one. If you do this Stefan – I promise you that you’ll never work in this industry again.” <em>“Are you threatening my client?”</em> says David. “No, Mr. Offenbach &#8211; it’s a promise.”</p>
<p><strong>NOW IT’S WAR</strong></p>
<p>In a way, Alan Sapper is right. No one can sue a union. The Wilson/ Callaghan government has seen to that. David says they are acting like feudal barons and we can sue the ACTT executives. He asks for names and addresses and is told to get lost.</p>
<p>David obtains a court order forcing the ACTT to send us the names and home addresses of their executives. Someone at 2 Soho Square mistakenly thinks the court order is requesting a full document disclosure. The next day, delivered by courier to David’s Bond Street office, there arrives a large file with all ACTT/ Molinare correspondence. It’s a gold mine.</p>
<p><strong>LETTERS FROM SOHO SQUARE</strong></p>
<p>The gem is a letter from the union to the management of competitive facilities companies asking them if Molinare were permitted to use 1” tape and new technology, would they lose business? There are replies from my competitors saying <em>keep Molinare black</em>.</p>
<p>David Offenbach, a sincere, idealistic socialist, is horrified. “Trade unions are there to protect worker’s rights – and here they are writing to top management. It’s like the Mafia consulting the Feds.”</p>
<p>Geoffrey Robertson agrees; the ACTT has blown it.</p>
<p>Outside the Royal Courts of Justice on The Strand, Sapper comes up to me. “Are you sure you want to do this? There’s still time to back out.”</p>
<p><strong>SHOWTIME</strong></p>
<p>Inside the Law Courts, the barristers stand and make their cases. Then a surprise, the ACTT’s barrister is called over by Sapper. He returns and tells the judge that the ACTT will meet all Molinare demands. The new technology is approved for use at Molinare. All Moli staff can join the union – remember this is in the days of <em>the closed shop</em>, there will be no backlash, no reprisals; in short &#8211; a walkover victory.</p>
<p>Outside, braving the traffic noise, Alan Sapper greets me like an old friend. “We never thought you’d have the nerve to go all the way. We’re good losers. No hard feelings …” I force a smile and shake hands. <em>“So I can still work in the business?” </em></p>
<p><strong>A PICNIC IN THE PARK</strong></p>
<p>Tricia makes a picnic and we eat in the park, on the grass, outside 2 Soho Square. We toast the shiny black door. Bliss …</p>
<p>Returning to Molinare, our receptionist hands me a box. Inside is a large chocolate cake with a handwritten note: “From Kerry, Jane, Max and the folks at LWT. Congratulations. Well done.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/2013/05/25/black-is-black-i-want-my-facility-back/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CH CH CH CH CHANGES</title>
		<link>/2013/04/24/ch-ch-ch-ch-changes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2013 19:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1531</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TURN AND FACE THE STRAIn I make a little film—no, I mean video &#8211; for Mary. She comes here, sees it once and loves it. “Put it on our YouTube channel and make me a couple of DVDs.” Six Kodak &#8230; <a href="/2013/04/24/ch-ch-ch-ch-changes/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>TURN AND FACE THE STRAIn<br />
</strong><br />
I make a little film—no, I mean video &#8211; for Mary. She comes here, sees it once and loves it.</p>
<div id="content-area">
<div id="node-62485">
<div>
<p><em>“Put it on our YouTube channel and make me a couple of DVDs.”</em></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/05Learn-ProdDiary-Changes-1.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Six Kodak Carousel projectors controlled by either Electrosonic or AVL boxes</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>“Want to see it again?”</p>
<p><em>“No, it’s perfect. Send me the invoice.”</em></p>
<p>A week later, via e-mail: <em>“Stefan, we all love it but the general feeling is we should add a title at the start. Ken has written some words&#8230;.”</em></p>
<p>How come last week it was perfect and now it needs a title?</p>
<p>“Mary, while making changes in video is easy, YouTube will not let you insert shots into an existing video. I’ll have to replace it with a new video. Oh, and shall I scrap the two DVDs?”</p>
<p><em>“Sorry Stefan, I thought you could just add a title.”</em></p>
<p>How I hate changes, and who’s this guy Ken? I find his web site. OMG, he’s a <em>multimedia consultant.</em> Spare me!</p>
<p><strong>Days of Wine and Roses</strong></p>
<p>It wasn’t always like this. In the good old days of film—yes, I mean <em>film</em>—when finished and client-approved, the whole lot went off to the lab.</p>
<p>The ice froze over and changes were nigh impossible. Yeah!</p>
<p>If changes were really necessary, it became a BIG DEAL, with a new quote and a week of expensive lab work.</p>
<p><em>Those were the days my friend, those were the days.</em></p>
<p><strong>The Beginning of the End</strong></p>
<p>In 1980, I build the <em>Moliplexer</em>. It has six projectors with a choice of dissolve modules, a TEAC 4-track 1/4-inch and a Philips LDK33 camera. Using all six projectors, you can change slides at 5p. That’s five frames a second.</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/05Learn-ProdDiary-Changes-2.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>It’s a huge, booked-out success. In Molinare’s complex of television studios, edit suites and audio studios, the <em>Moliplexer</em> is the top money-spinner, the undisputed cash cow.</p>
<p>Little do I realize: it’s also the beginning of the end. Finally, clients can make instant changes. No need to wait for the lab.</p>
<p>There you go, Ken—pop in that extra slide. Oh, it’s a title at the start. In it goes. Ping! See if I care&#8230;.</p>
<p><strong>Jump Cuts Are Cool</strong></p>
<p>And then there’s Wayne. No, that’s not his real name—but Wayne rhymes with Pain.</p>
<p>He phones me, tells me he’s fallen out with Neville, one of the interviewees in his video.</p>
<p><em>“Cut him out. It’s easy.”</em></p>
<p>He phones again. <em>“You know the guy who died last year, Oswald, we’ve still got his interview. When you take out Neville, replace him with the dead guy.”</em></p>
<p>“But he’s dead.”</p>
<p><em>“I have a signed release. Dedicate the DVD to him.”</em></p>
<p>It isn’t easy. Neville is all the way through and Oswald is saying different things. Wayne comes over to see the result.</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/05Learn-ProdDiary-Changes-3.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The legendary Jean-Luc Godard, inventor of the jump cut (so says Wayne)</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><em>“No, no. You’ve still got her </em>(another interviewee)<em> talking about Neville—cut it out.</em>”</p>
<p>“The whole interview?”</p>
<p><em>“No, only his name.”</em></p>
<p>“Just his name? It will jump.”</p>
<p><em>“Don’t tell me. It’s called a jump cut, invented by Jean-Luc Godard. Jump cuts are cool. Godard won a prize for it. Just do it.”</em></p>
<p>I do it. In the video, she’s about to say the forbidden name and &#8230; the picture jumps.</p>
<p>“Wayne, it looks as though I’ve cut his name out.”</p>
<p><em>“Good. I want the bastard to see it and know he’s been chopped out. Thank you, Jean-Luc.”</em></p>
<p>Clients! What would we do without them? Hmmm &#8230; not a bad idea.</p>
<p><em>So goodbye Mary, goodbye Wayne /</em></p>
<p><em>Will we ever meet again? </em></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stefan’s Giveaway:</title>
		<link>/2013/03/28/stefans-giveaway/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 18:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2013]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://prior.stefansargent.com/?p=1527</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A Tale of Two Cameras Published On: 03/19/13 03:03:38 PM By: Stefan Sargent Remember last month’s Production Diary? I wrote that I put my two Sony HVR-V1U camcorders on eBay. What a fiasco! AaarrrggghhhBAY Gee, I was only trying to sell &#8230; <a href="/2013/03/28/stefans-giveaway/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>A Tale of Two Cameras</h1>
<div id="content-area">
<div id="node-62063">
<div>
<div id="pdate">Published On: 03/19/13 03:03:38 PM</div>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div>By:</div>
<p>Stefan Sargent</p></div>
</div>
</div>
<p>Remember last month’s Production Diary? I wrote that I put my two <a href="http://pro.sony.com/bbsc/ssr/product-HVRV1U/">Sony HVR-V1U </a>camcorders on eBay. What a fiasco!</p>
<p><strong>AaarrrggghhhBAY</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/04Learn-ProdDiary-Giveaway-1.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Gee, I was only trying to sell a camera.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Winner of camera #1 complains that it is broken; the cassette mechanism is jammed open. Would I sell a broken camera? Of course not.</p>
<p>I pay for the UPS return and refund his money. And guess what? It really IS broken. Hmmm… No choice but to send it away to be repaired. Two lots of UPS shipping charges plus a $550 repair bill. Can it get worse? You bet…</p>
<p><strong>Worse and Worser</strong><br />
The winner of camera #2 thought he could buy now—pay later. No dice. Then he asks his mum. Nope, she won’t lend him money either.</p>
<p>I click an eBay button saying something like “buyer didn’t pay” and he goes BALLISTIC. His e-mails are in CAPITALS accusing me of VENGANCE and THREATING (his spelling, not mine).</p>
<p><strong>From Hate to Halo</strong><br />
Fate steps in. An e-mail from Peter Meyers, my first U.S. client, from ’99.</p>
<p><em>“Stef.”</em>—He always calls me Stef. I hate it.—<em>“Stef., Lucas wants a video camera—tell me what to buy him.”</em></p>
<p>Lucas is 12 and as smart as a tack. In ’99, he simply didn’t exist. Weird.<br />
“Oh Peter, have I got a camera for Lucas!”</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/04Learn-ProdDiary-Giveaway-2.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>Future movie director with his Sony HVR-V1U camera</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I wait until Peter’s Christmas party. Lucas can’t believe his eyes. He’s so happy.</p>
<p>We sit on the floor and I do a quick run-through of the camera.<em> Here’s the auto/manual switch. Use the ND filter for exterior shooting. You can drop the shutter speed in low-light conditions.</em> All meaningless mumbo jumbo, he’s just too excited to listen.</p>
<p><em>“Thank you! Thank you.”</em></p>
<p>He’s thrilled—so am I.</p>
<p>Final Cut Pro X<br />
It’s a month since Lucas received his camera. I’ll swing around this Saturday.</p>
<p>“How’s it going?” <em>“The camera doesn’t appear on the desktop, I can’t drag and drop.”</em></p>
<p>I’m about to explain that he has to use Apple FCP X, but he already knows. In fact, he’s shot and edited a dramatic short complete with actors. The timeline has added gunshot flashes and sound effects.</p>
<p><em>“Should I use library music or compose my own?”</em></p>
<p><strong>My Giveaway to You</strong><br />
I still have that other camera. It came back from the repairers looking like new, with a six-month guarantee.</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/images/04Learn-ProdDiary-Giveaway-3.JPG" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>The Sony V1U comes in this nifty case—with all accessories, battery, charger, tape stock and owner manual.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Will it be you? I’m looking for another Herzog, Rodriguez or Tarantino. When fame and fortune eventually strikes, just say you owe it all to me.<br />
How to Win</p>
<p>Simply e-mail Cristina, our beloved editor, a few lines about why you should win my camera and what you want to do with it. No more than 250 words. The e-mail subject line must be GIVEAWAY. Entries to be in by May 1, 2013. The winner will be announced in the July 2013 issue. Here’s the e-mail address: <a href="mailto:cclapp@nbmedia.com?subject=GIVEAWAY">cclapp@nbmedia.com</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Not So Fine Print</strong><br />
Your name and the winning e-mail will be published. I want to see some amazing videos from you on YouTube.</p>
<p>Dare to sell the camera on aarrgghhBay: you will have your subscription to<em> Digital Video</em> magazine canceled, a horse’s head placed on your pillow, and the bad fairies will come and get you.</p>
<p>Now write that winning e-mail. Good luck</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div id="content-area">
<div id="node-62063"></div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
