<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>2016 &#8211; Stefan Sargent</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/2016/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:25:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>THREE WEDDINGS AND A VIMEO</title>
		<link>/2016/12/20/three-weddings-and-a-vimeo/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:25:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=2017</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Where KISS Is an Acronym 1. Bad Zipper – Fun Wedding In the photo, a very young Stefan is pretending to monitor the sound. On my left is school friend Robert Parker. We record weddings on a Ferrograph tape recorder &#8230; <a href="/2016/12/20/three-weddings-and-a-vimeo/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Where KISS Is an Acronym</strong></p>
<p><strong> </strong></p>
<p style="text-align: center;">
<p><span style="font-weight: bold; font-size: 16px;"> </span></p>
<div id="attachment_2040" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/rob-ss-wedding2.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2040" class="size-full wp-image-2040" title="rob ss wedding" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/rob-ss-wedding2.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="480" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2040" class="wp-caption-text">We are both wearing dark suits because that’s what you do at weddings in 1962.</p></div>
<p><strong>1. Bad Zipper – Fun Wedding </strong><br />
In the photo, a very young Stefan is pretending to monitor the sound. On my left is school friend Robert Parker. We record weddings on a Ferrograph tape recorder and burn two 12-inch LPs—one “sealed in plastic to last a lifetime.”</p>
<p>This particular wedding has ground to a halt. The bride entered the church and took a deep breath before going down the aisle. ZIP—ZAP—POW! <em>Disaster</em>. The zipper on her new wedding dress self-destructs.</p>
<p>She screams and reverses backwards out of the church. You can imagine what the groom at the altar is thinking.</p>
<p>Now she is running down the street hoping to find a friendly house where she can have her wide-open dress sewn up. The congregation is told, and we all settle down to listen to an endless organ recital. “<em>By the Sea, By the Beautiful Sea.”</em></p>
<p>The wedding photographer is wandering around. He discovers our recording hideout, we do a busy pose and he snaps us up. Finally, the bride returns in a borrowed red and yellow dress. We applaud her entrance, she cries,<em> they live happily ever after.</em></p>
<p><strong>2. Bad Host – No Wedding<br />
</strong>We’re at Rosemary and Miles’ place. It’s Miles’ birthday and the table has about ten other guests. Much of the dinner talk is about their daughter’s wedding.</p>
<p>“<em>Stefan, you will film it, won’t you?”</em> All the guests are waiting for my response. I had said no a week earlier. Here we go again.</p>
<p>“No, Rosemary, I won’t film the wedding. I’m not a wedding filmmaker.”</p>
<p><em>“But Stefan, please take some shots—just home movie stuff.”</em></p>
<p>The table is now dead quiet as Rosemary and I are locked in battle. “Rosemary, I make corporate videos. That’s my profession. I’ve made a strict policy not to do videos for friends. It’s as simple as that.”</p>
<p>A week later a letter arrives:</p>
<p><em>Dearest Stefan and Tricia,</em></p>
<p><em>We asked too many people to Rebecca’s wedding and have decided to cut back on the numbers. It is with regret that we have to withdraw our wedding invitation.</em></p>
<p>—<em>Rosemary</em></p>
<p><strong>3. KISS Is an Acronym</strong></p>
<p>My son William and his love Megan are getting married at our place. I can shoot it “professionally” with three cameras:</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody></tbody>
</table>
<p>1. CENTER a wide shot</p>
<p>2. RIGHT a CU on Megan</p>
<p>3. LEFT a CU on Will</p>
<p>And maybe 4. REVERSE ANGLE?</p>
<p>Four cameras, four tripods, and what about some lights and three radio mics? Come on, that’s crazy, it’s a small family wedding.<a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/12Expertise-ProdDiary-WeddingVimeo-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-2024" title="12Expertise-ProdDiary-WeddingVimeo-2" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/12Expertise-ProdDiary-WeddingVimeo-2-1024x546.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="341" /></a></p>
<p>My way is always the KISS way: <em>Keep It Simple, Stupid</em>. No lights, just one handheld camera, plus a fixed, reverse angle GoPro.</p>
<div id="attachment_2025" style="width: 410px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/gopro-wedding.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2025" class="size-full wp-image-2025" title="gopro wedding" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/12/gopro-wedding.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="795" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2025" class="wp-caption-text">Reverse angle GoPro clamped to a table lamp with Gorilla legs. I’m too lazy to remove one camera from the dual 3D casing.</p></div>
<p style="text-align: center;">My Sony HXR-NX30’s stabilization is so good, I can move from left and right, get in close and pull back.</p>
<p>My son’s wedding is online: <em><a href="https://vimeo.com/158444586">vimeo.com/158444586</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WHERE HAVE ALL THE DIGI-TRAILS GONE?</title>
		<link>/2016/11/03/where-have-all-the-digi-trails-gone/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2016 04:28:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=2009</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Nonlinear Editing Killed Them, Every One At the Exploratorium, Tricia is raising her arm and creating digi-trails in real time. We’re here at San Francisco’s Exploratorium to see Dutch artist Theo Jansen’s Strandbeest exhibition. One of his many kinetic sculptures &#8230; <a href="/2016/11/03/where-have-all-the-digi-trails-gone/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<h1>Nonlinear Editing Killed Them, Every One</h1>
</div>
<div>
<p><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/exporatorium-live-effect-1000.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2035" title="exporatorium-live-effect-1000" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/exporatorium-live-effect-1000.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="1034" /></a>At the Exploratorium, Tricia is raising her arm and creating digi-trails in real time.</p>
<p>We’re here at San Francisco’s Exploratorium to see Dutch artist Theo Jansen’s Strandbeest exhibition. One of his many kinetic sculptures struts its stuff. Jaw dropping!</p>
<p>Eventually we wander off to, dare I say it, <em>explore</em> the Exploratorium. We enter an empty room and see ourselves projected in posterized color with digi-trails following our every move.</p>
<p>“OMG,” I say to Tricia, “It’s SqueeZoom from the 1980s. You can’t do that these days.”</p>
<p><strong>The Big Squeeze</strong></p>
<p>At home, I dig out my old videos from the SqueeZoom days. The Molinare 1980 showreel is packed with them—trails, trails and more trails. Then, so hip and of the moment; today, crude and dated. But love is blind and I love them all. (Watch the 1980 Molinare showreel, hosted by James Smiley <a href="http://vimeo.com/65027881">here</a>. )</p>
<p>My Vital Industries SqueeZoom edit suite with four VTRs is £400 an hour. Booked almost seven days a week, it pays for itself in six months.</p>
<p><strong>Tonight I Get High</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img class="aligncenter" src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/public/11Expert-ProdDiary-2.jpg" alt="" width="600" height="439" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>From the Molinare showreel</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Tricia and I live on the top floor of Molinare, our video facility. I love my new toy so much that on the rare occasion when it isn’t booked, I sneak downstairs with my own VCR and plug into SqueeZoom. Tra la!</p>
<p>I am the Wizard of Oz! Effect 51—trails galore. Effect 67—the image does multiple repeats. Finally I feed SqueeZoom back into itself and out comes endless streaming, changing colors, digi-trailing to infinity.</p>
<p>Where’s my copy of <em>The Crazy World of Arthur Brown</em>?</p>
<p><strong>Ampex ADO</strong></p>
<p>Four years after SqueeZoom, I buy an ADO (Ampex Digital Optics). Sadly, SqueeZoom can’t rotate the picture XYZ and can’t do perspective, but ADO can and more.</p>
<p>It’s $150,000 and as revolutionary as the SqueeZoom was in her short life.</p>
<p>Today, late 2016, I buy an ADO control unit on eBay for $29.99 including shipping.</p>
<p><strong>Ballet Trails</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/encore-ballet-1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2032" title="encore-ballet-1" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/encore-ballet-1.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="754" /></a>From the 1985 Quantel Encore promo</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/encore-ballet-2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2033" title="encore-ballet-2" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/encore-ballet-2.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="752" /></a><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/encore-ballet-1000.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2034" title="encore-ballet-1000" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/encore-ballet-1000.jpg" alt="" width="1000" height="747" /></a>My favorite trail video is the ballet dancer in my 1985 Quantel Encore DVE promo—$160,00 a snip but so beautiful.</p>
<p><strong>Vintage Treasures</strong></p>
<p>You can’t do these effects anymore—not in Adobe After Effects, Apple Motion, Boris FX, Apple Final Cut Pro X, GenArts Sapphire, Red Giant TrapCode, Tiffen DFX, you name it. Sure you can make wishy-washy trails and blurs and a zillion cute particle effects, but they don’t even come close to these real-time hardware-created babies.</p>
<p>Digi-trails—gone the way of Bakelite ashtrays, lava lamps, VW T3 vans, Sinclair ZX computers &#8230; and whatever happened to Arthur Brown?</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>CONNECTIONS</title>
		<link>/2016/09/28/2000/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2016 15:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=2000</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Goof Off and Die Ever walk away from your real-world obligations and just have fun? Be warned&#8230; I’m co-owner and CEO of Molinare, the largest video facility company in London. Clive Burke is a Molinare client. He’s always in with &#8230; <a href="/2016/09/28/2000/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<h1>Goof Off and Die</h1>
</div>
<div>
<div><span style="font-size: 16px;">Ever walk away from your real-world obligations and just have fun? Be warned&#8230;</span></div>
<p>I’m co-owner and CEO of Molinare, the largest video facility company in London.</p>
<p><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/electrosonic-3601-800px.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2005" title="electrosonic 3601 800px" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/electrosonic-3601-800px.jpg" alt="" width="594" height="935" /></a>Clive Burke is a Molinare client. He’s always in with his twin carousel slide shows. He loves his Electrosonic ES3601 slide projector presentation system.</p>
<p><strong>Enter the Elevator</strong></p>
<p>“Clive, film is so much better than a two-projector show.”</p>
<p><em>“Funny you should say that. I have a job for Pearson’s Pottery in Chesterfield.”</em></p>
<p>I need time off from being a suit and tie executive to get back to my craft. Hey, it’s only two days.</p>
<p><strong>Going Down<a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/connections-dvd-set.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-2006" title="connections dvd set" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/connections-dvd-set.jpg" alt="" width="500" height="568" /></a><br />
</strong></p>
<p>Clive likes our film and tells his famous brother, James Burke. James hosts a science series, <em>Connections</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Down, Down, Down</strong></p>
<p>A few weeks later—<em>yes, I should be running Moli</em>—it’s another shoot, a corporate about Perkins diesel engines. We are in the noisiest factory ever with brother James. The factory is so loud that I can’t hear him clearly on my headphones.</p>
<p>When I check, the sound is unusable; that’s never happened to me before or since. So bad that if Perkins has any sense, they will fire me and sue for Burke’s fee.</p>
<p><strong>Ground Floor</strong></p>
<p>Incredibly, the Perkins people are delighted and want me to do another job.</p>
<p><em>They liked my awful film!</em> These Perkins guys are idiots, but then again, so am I. Alarm bells should be ringing. <em>Ding! Ding!</em> But no, I’ll do the gig. Not a two-day wonder but two weeks away in Scandinavia!</p>
<div id="attachment_2007" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Rutschebanen-wooden-roller-coaster-at-Bakken-Denmark-tunnel-entrance.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-2007" class="size-large wp-image-2007" title="Rutschebanen wooden roller coaster at Bakken, Denmark - tunnel entrance" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/Rutschebanen-wooden-roller-coaster-at-Bakken-Denmark-tunnel-entrance-1024x576.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="360" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-2007" class="wp-caption-text">Rutschebanen roller coaster at Bakken</p></div>
<p>First day in Denmark, the two Perkins guys and I are on the Rutschebanen wooden roller coaster at Bakken, which is bigger and better than the one at Tivoli Gardens.</p>
<p>In the afternoon, it’s the Carlsberg &amp; Jacobsen Brewhouse tour. At night, we do Copenhagen.</p>
<p>Next day, I check how many boatyard locations we are visiting.</p>
<p>“Let’s see, five in Denmark, six in Norway, six in Sweden and five in Finland.”</p>
<p>“OMG, that’s 22. I don’t have enough film to shoot them all.”</p>
<p><em>“Stefan, this is a PR exercise. They’re really excited about our visit. We don’t have the budget for more film. Shoot two in each country, pretend to shoot the rest.”</em></p>
<p><strong>Six Feet Under</strong></p>
<p>We arrive at a boatyard; the owner is pleased to see us. My 16mm Éclair camera has an empty magazine. The red light comes on. The Perkins sales rep does a long interview but nothing is shot. I’m faking it. I feel bad, very bad.</p>
<p>We leave Denmark and make our way up Norway. There’s a lot of partying, saunas, drinking and shooting with no film. Next is Sweden—yep, more partying, saunas, drinking, more no-film shooting; followed by Finland, did I say party? Then suddenly the two from Perkins have to leave.</p>
<p>I’m stuck in Helsinki. Whaaa!</p>
<p><strong>Shame and Pain</strong></p>
<p>If I had let Clive Burke stick with his beloved ES3601, none of this would have happened. These two shameful works of crap were the last films I made for eight years.</p>
<p><em>They got a name for the winners in the world,</em></p>
<p><em>I want a name when I lose. </em></p>
</div>
<div>Want to read more stories like thi</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>DCP BFD</title>
		<link>/2016/09/06/dcp-bfd/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 01:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=1988</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kiss Your &#8216;Cinema Paradiso&#8217; Goodbye FYI: The world has changed. The movies you see at the cinema are no longer projected from 35mm film. Instead, the moving images are coming from a computer hard drive. The DCP (digital cinema package) &#8230; <a href="/2016/09/06/dcp-bfd/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<h1>Kiss Your &#8216;Cinema Paradiso&#8217; Goodbye</h1>
</div>
<div>
<div>
<div id="attachment_1995" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/cinema-paradiso.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1995" class="size-large wp-image-1995" title="cinema-paradiso" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/cinema-paradiso-1024x709.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="443" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1995" class="wp-caption-text">Cinema Paradiso (1988) is an Academy Award-winning Italian film about a young boy and his projectionist friend.</p></div>
</div>
<p>FYI: The world has changed. The movies you see at the cinema are no longer projected from 35mm film. Instead, the moving images are coming from a computer hard drive. The DCP (digital cinema package) stored on the hard drive is a collection of files containing digital cinema audio, image and data streams.</p>
<p>DCP is also a TLA. What’s a TLA? A three-letter acronym, like IBM, TSA and WTF.</p>
<p>A DCP has TIFF format video in (here come the TLAs) XYZ color space, with audio in PCM multichannel WAV encrypted in AES 128-bit in CBC mode, all wrapped in an MXF container. It’s TLAs from start to finish. Not for humble DIY folk like you and me.</p>
<p><strong>Who You Gonna Call? Do Busters!</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/public/09Learn-ProdDiary-DCPBFD-2.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>David’s double-width master has two SBS (side-by-side) 1920 x 1080 L &amp; R frames.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>My film <em>WBAS</em> (<em>We Built a Ship</em>) has been selected for screening at the NMFF (New Media Film Festival). They want a 3D DCP.</p>
<p>Before commissioning a DCP, I decide to get a 3D Blu-ray (BD3D) made.</p>
<p>I do a search and find Sony Creative Software DoStudio 3D. At $20K, I wonder who has bought Do software. I discover a link to user David Courtice, CEO of DC Creative in L.A.</p>
<p><strong>I Need a BD3D</strong></p>
<p>I USPS a PNY 256 GB USB 3.0 flash drive with separate left- and right-eye ProRes files.</p>
<p><em>“Stefan, </em><em>I have your USB drive. The masters you sent are 1080i 29.97. The only acceptable frame sizes/rates for BD3D are 1920 x 1080 @ 23.976 fps progressive or 1280 x 720 @ 59.94 fps progressive. </em><em>I suggest we downconvert to 720p/59.94 and then encode.”</em></p>
<p>“OMG, what a PIA! OTY, David, make the BD3D at 720p.”</p>
<p><strong>MNG (Meet and Greet) F2F</strong></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/public/09Learn-ProdDiary-DCPBFD-3.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>A feature-length movie is about five 2,000-foot reels of 35mm film—all replaced by this single hard drive.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I have my full-length Blu-ray duplicated copies; now I need a 17-minute DCP for the NMFF 3D screening in Los Angeles.</p>
<p>I jet from SFO to BUR and meet David F2F. He’s running a boutique facility with editing, color grading and sound design rooms.</p>
<p>To convert my film to 24p, he makes and renders a 3840 double-width master in Adobe After Effects. It takes a day to cook. When finished, he breaks it back into separate left and right files. There follows a litany of XYZ, TIFF, MXF, PCM and WAV work—you don’t want to know. David speaks TLA like a native.</p>
<p>We go to indieDCP in Burbank. They make the final DCP. We put on our passive 3D glasses for the preview screening. No longer <em>Cinema Paradiso</em>, now <em>Cinema DCP-o</em>.</p>
<p><strong>We Won!</strong></p>
<p>At the NMFF, our DCP is presented on a huge screen. The 3D is great; folks in front of me duck as 3D sawdust comes spewing out. <em>WBAS</em> is awarded Best 3D. Yeah! “I.G.Y. (What a Beautiful World)<em>.”</em></p>
<p>My thanks to David (DC Creative), Bryan (indieDCP), Brandon (drone pilot), Tricia (producer and second camera), Alan and all the crew at the shipyard.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ALL THE WORLD&#8217;S A STAGE</title>
		<link>/2016/07/25/all-the-worlds-a-stage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 15:35:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=1973</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[But Let’s Make It Look Like a Movie Working as a cameraman for director Ken Russell was scary. One mistake and you’re out. Pity the poor PA who quipped that a shot of Ken’s looked like one from Ingmar Bergman’s &#8230; <a href="/2016/07/25/all-the-worlds-a-stage/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>But Let’s Make It Look Like a Movie</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1981" style="width: 810px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Janet_Suzman_RSC_1963-8002.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1981" class="size-full wp-image-1981" title="Janet_Suzman_RSC_1963-800" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Janet_Suzman_RSC_1963-8002.jpg" alt="" width="800" height="539" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1981" class="wp-caption-text">Janet Suzman as Joan of Arc falls through the floor and is burned at the stake. Bummer.</p></div>
<p>Working as a cameraman for director Ken Russell was scary. One mistake and you’re out. Pity the poor PA who quipped that a shot of Ken’s looked like one from Ingmar Bergman’s <em>Wild Strawberries</em>.</p>
<p><em>&#8220;Beam me up, Kennie!”</em> Where’d he go?</p>
<p>Tonight I’m going to work as an editor with director Peter Hall and writer John Barton. Together, they founded the Royal Shakespeare Company. I’m nervous. Will this be my BBC swan song?</p>
<p><strong>FRIDAY NIGHT</strong><br />
It’s 6 p.m. and they’re here in my cutting room viewing my week’s work. Peter couldn’t be more different from the irascible Ken. While he knows Shakespeare and theater backwards, film editing and postproduction are new to him.</p>
<p>Peter: <em>“</em><em>Do you understand that we want it to look like a feature film rather than a stage production?&#8221;</em></p>
<p><em> </em>Yes.” <em>“Having seen it, do you have any suggestions?”<br />
</em><br />
“The whole production could be tightened up. There are long pauses where actors walk in or leave the stage.”</p>
<p><em>“Chop away. Do whatever looks best. We’re in your hands.”<br />
</em><br />
“Next, the rhyming couplets at the end of each scene don’t work. They reek of a stage production.”</p>
<p><em>“Agreed—cut them out. Shakespeare isn’t sacred.”</em><br />
John:<em> “It’s called the WARS of the Roses. There are wars going on all the time. We shot some real cannons and soldiers fighting, but with hindsight, not nearly enough. There need to be battles scattered over the nine-hour series. You could even interrupt a scene with one. Create new battles from scraps. </em><em>Étonne-moi.”<br />
</em><br />
Amaze me! What a challenge.</p>
<p><strong>MONDAY MORNING</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1986" style="width: 796px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Citizen-Kane-Filming-Low-Angle1.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1986" class="size-full wp-image-1986" title="Citizen-Kane-Filming-Low-Angle" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/Citizen-Kane-Filming-Low-Angle1.jpg" alt="" width="786" height="619" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1986" class="wp-caption-text">Orson Wells and Gregg (I need a fag) Toland line up a low-angle shot</p></div>
<p>I can’t wait to see my editing FOM, Simeon. Gleefully, he can’t wait to gossip about an RSC screw-up.</p>
<p><em>“They cut a hole in the expensive new stage to get low-angle shots.”<br />
</em><br />
“Probably copying Orson Wells, who did the same for <em>Citizen Kane</em>.”</p>
<p><em>“<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Janet_Suzman">Janet Suzman</a> as Joan of Arc comes running with her sword upraised, there’s lots of smoke and, whoosh, she disappears down into the camera pit. She sprains her ankle badly and limps right up to the time she’s taken away and burned at the stake.”</em></p>
<p><strong>BUDGET: WHAT BUDGET?</strong><br />
“Simeon, John Barton wants me to add mini-wars throughout the nine hours. I can do it but I’m worried about the number of film opticals. The lab costs could be in the thousands.”</p>
<p><em>“No worries. It’s below the line.”<br />
</em><br />
“I don’t understand.”</p>
<p><em>“Below the line, like when you need a new chinagraph pencil or a replacement lamp. Film opticals are the same. This is Aunty BBC, not the real world.”</em></p>
<p><strong>ALL&#8217;S WELL THAT ENDS WELL</strong><br />
The nine-hour program is a great success. I am offered a full-time staff job. It would be safe and cozy. I pass, needing the <em>slings and arrows of outrageous fortune—</em>and friends, they were all there waiting for me.</p>
<p><em>Outrageous fortune</em> indeed! I should be so lucky.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BRUSH UP YOUR SHAKESPEARE</title>
		<link>/2016/07/03/brush-up-your-shakespeare/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 16:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=1964</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Right Back Where I Started From Yay! I’m back at BBC Ealing. I’m so happy! I run up the stairs to the room with all the FOMs. “Hi Fred, hi Derek, hi Simeon. I’m an editor now!” Simeon is the &#8230; <a href="/2016/07/03/brush-up-your-shakespeare/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<h1>Right Back Where I Started From</h1>
<h1><span style="font-size: 16px;">Yay! I’m back at BBC Ealing. I’m so happy! I run up the stairs to the room with all the FOMs. “Hi Fred, hi Derek, hi Simeon. I’m an editor now!”</span></h1>
</div>
<div>
<p>Simeon is the film operations manager for editors. We go down the stairs to the BBC canteen. He can’t wait to tell me about the strange and wonderful ways of BBC editing.</p>
<p><em>“Stefan, we’ve got Ampex VR1000 videotape recorders. Right? Well,</em><em> they cost £40,000 and are bloody useless. Video editing is a disaster. You can’t splice the 2-inch tape. They say you can, but in practice you can’t, and it ruins the tape anyhow. The show you’ll be working on, </em>The Wars of the Roses<em>, is a 35mm telerecording </em>[kinescope or kine in the United States]<em> from live cameras.”</em></p>
<p><strong>Hey Bra’ What’s Da Kine?</strong></p>
<p>“A telerecording [kine] is film. Film, we all know and love. A 35mm synchronized camera shoots a 405-line cathode ray tube. It shows a negative image so the processed film is positive. Are you following me?</p>
<p><em>“Peter Hall, the boss of the Royal Shakespeare Company, wanted to do it on the stage at Stratford on Avon. A bloody stupid idea, if you ask me. They had to pull out seating and completely rebuild the sloping stage to make it flat. Why? They could have done it in our TV studios. We had to run in land lines to the center and record it as a 35mm telerecording. Madness&#8230;</em></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/public/07Learn-ProdDiary-Shakespeare-1.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td><em>The Wars of the Roses</em> aired on BBC1 in April 1965.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p><em>“To complicate everything, they shot each sequence four or five times, moving the six cameras to different positions. Each pass, the director called the shots, so the cutting is different. Eight weeks shooting with over 50 BBC staff on location and who knows how many RSC people. Did I say ‘madness’ already?”</em></p>
<p><strong>Binge Television 1965 Style</strong></p>
<p>“All that effort and it winds up in a room here in Ealing, cans and tapes from floor to ceiling. Three three-hour programs—a nine-hour marathon to be broadcast over three days. And it’s all yours, my boy!”</p>
<p>“Gee, thanks, Simeon. But don’t you have a real, full-time editor?”</p>
<p><em>“Frankly, no one wanted the job. We dumped it on Nobby Clark, but Shakespeare is not his thing. You understand Shakespeare, can do Shakespeare, can’t you?”</em></p>
<p>“Sure. ‘If she says your behavior is heinous, kick her right in the Coriolanus.’”</p>
<p><em>“Shakespeare?”</em></p>
<p><em>“No, Cole Porter.”</em></p>
<p><strong>Fire Burn and Keller Bubble</strong></p>
<div id="attachment_1966" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/35mm_KEM_flatbed.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1966" class="size-large wp-image-1966" title="35mm_KEM_flatbed" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/35mm_KEM_flatbed-1024x862.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="538" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1966" class="wp-caption-text">Our edit room has a six-plate 35mm Keller flatbed.</p></div>
<p>I meet Nobby and look at the half hour he has cut. There’s a freeze-frame that stands out. I try to be tactful.</p>
<p>“Nobby, you can see the film grain suddenly stops on the freeze.”</p>
<p><em>“I know. I had to extend the scene.”</em></p>
<p>“Then what you must do is find a spot where you can run the film back and forward, back and forward. That way the film grain keeps moving.”</p>
<p><em>“Brilliant. You take over. I will look after labels and cut the M&amp;E rolls. Peter Hall and John Barton will be in this Friday night to review our work—no, I mean, your work.”</em></p>
<p>Nobby has backed out, it’s my baby. I have five days to prove myself before they come.</p>
<p><em>Fear no more the frown of the great.</em></p>
<p>To be continued.</p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BLAZE OF GLORY</title>
		<link>/2016/05/29/blaze-of-glory/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2016 21:39:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=1946</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[My Secret Life as Jennifer Beals My four-month holiday relief job at the BBC is over. One more visit to say goodbye to my FOM, Fred. “You heard? He burnt my clapper.” “Great story. Westbury said you tried to save &#8230; <a href="/2016/05/29/blaze-of-glory/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>My Secret Life as Jennifer Beals</h1>
<p>My four-month holiday relief job at the BBC is over. One more visit to say goodbye to my FOM, Fred.</p>
<p>“You heard? He burnt my clapper.”</p>
<p><em>“Great story. Westbury said you tried to save it. You leave us in blaze of glory…”</em></p>
<p>“Very funny. Any chance of a last-minute reprieve?”</p>
<p><em>“No. In fact, I have to cut back on camera crews—25 to maybe 20. Tough decisions for me. But try Derek in sound. He might have something. Derek, ask him a few of your famous questions!”</em></p>
<p>Derek is the film operations manager for sound. He’s a desk away.</p>
<p><em>“So you think you know about sound?”</em></p>
<p>“I started in radio and did wedding recordings.”</p>
<p><em>“You’ll need more than that to get into film sound at the BBC. I’ll start with a simple question.” </em>I am expecting him to ask me something like, What’s the difference between a VU and a PPM meter? But no. <em>“Tell me all you know about power amplifiers.”</em> It’s a below-the-belt question with zero relevance for film sound. <em>“Come on. Power amps.”</em></p>
<div id="attachment_1958" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/807_amp.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1958" class="size-large wp-image-1958" title="Exif_JPEG_PICTURE" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/807_amp-830x1024.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="789" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1958" class="wp-caption-text">Power amplifier with push-pull 5B/854Ms - basically slimmed down 807 tubes.</p></div>
<p>“Power amps! I love them—807s in push-pull. I prefer Class B, although AB has its merits. Shall I draw a circuit diagram and include the EF86 preamps?”</p>
<p>The other FOMs fall about laughing. A year before, I had built an 807 Class B power amplifier from a kit set. Derek has no choice; I start the next week as a sound recordist.</p>
<p><strong>EIGHT DAYS A WEEK<br />
</strong>Forgive me if I skip through the next awful six months doing sound. I’m out in the freezing British weather holding a boom mic over people’s heads–naturally I get the flu. On my return, I’m in a small room transferring location Nagra tapes to 16mm magnetic film.</p>
<p>I work 12-hour shifts every two days: Mon/Tue on, Wed/Thu off, Fri/Sat on, Sun/Mon off, and so on. It’s hell in my little prison cell. I am no longer on holiday relief; I’m stuck here for good. Ugh!</p>
<p><strong>THE BOARD<br />
</strong>I’ve been at the BBC almost a year and this is my annual review. It’s like the last sequence in <em>Flashdance</em>: a long table filled with respectable BBC executives and I’m Jennifer Beals.</p>
<div id="attachment_1959" style="width: 650px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/jennifer-beals-flashdance.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1959" class="size-large wp-image-1959" title="jennifer-beals-flashdance" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/jennifer-beals-flashdance-1024x538.jpg" alt="" width="640" height="336" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1959" class="wp-caption-text">Jennifer Beals in Flashdance</p></div>
<p><em>“Hello, Stefan. We’re delighted to meet you. You were a cameraman and then transferred to sound. Why did you make that move?”</em></p>
<p>“Not my choice. My holiday relief cameraman job ran out and I was offered sound, but I hate it. I’m just transferring tapes all day.”</p>
<p><em>“What would you like to do? Don’t say, ‘I want to direct.’”</em></p>
<p>“Take me out of sound. I can edit. I really can. I’ve made hundreds of pop videos and commercials in Australia. I can mark up 35mm film for optics.”</p>
<p>Me as Jennifer Beals flying through the air. The man at the end of the table picks up interest.</p>
<p><em>“There’s a mountain of 35mm film waiting for you to edit at Ealing Studios. It’s a three-part, nine-hour series, </em>The Wars of the Roses<em>. Report to your edit FOM next Monday.”</em></p>
<p><em>What a feeling, being’s believin’.</em></p>
<p style="text-align: right;"><em>To be continued&#8230; </em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>KEN RUSSELL BURNED MY CLAPPER</title>
		<link>/2016/05/03/ken-russell-burned-my-clapper/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 23:58:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=1922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8216;Z Cars&#8217; It Ain’t I am employed at BBC Ealing Studios as a cameraman. Well, that’s what I thought until I met my FOM, film operations manager Fred, and I discovered I am just a “holiday relief” cameraman, grade C &#8230; <a href="/2016/05/03/ken-russell-burned-my-clapper/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div>
<h1>&#8216;Z Cars&#8217; It Ain’t</h1>
<div id="attachment_1927" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/05Learn-ProdDiary-KenRussell-11.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1927" class="size-full wp-image-1927" title="05Learn-ProdDiary-KenRussell-1" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/05Learn-ProdDiary-KenRussell-11.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="488" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1927" class="wp-caption-text">Stefan on speedboat with ARRIFLEX 35 IIC, foreground Ken Russell, inset Oliver Reed</p></div>
</div>
<div>
<div><span style="font-size: 16px;">I am employed at BBC Ealing Studios as a cameraman. Well, that’s what I thought until I met my FOM, film operations manager Fred, and I discovered I am just a “holiday relief” cameraman, grade C minus. A three-month temporary assistant&#8230;</span></div>
<p>Fred takes pity on me, and for my swan song he puts me on Ken Russell’s <em>The Debussy Film</em>. It’s to be shot by BBC staff cameraman Ken Westbury. I had worked with him before on the BBC television series <em>Z Cars</em>, shooting 16mm. We know each other and get on well.</p>
<p><strong>DAY ONE<br />
</strong>The location is Beachy Head, near the seaside resort of Eastbourne. The call sheet says “Martyrdom of Saint Sebastian<em>.”</em> It is a long, difficult clamber over the rocks.</p>
<p>We have two ARRIFLEX 35 IIC 35mm cameras, tripods, batteries, a blimp, film magazines, boxes of film and lenses, including a heavy Angenieux 25-250 zoom. Slowed down by all the kit, we finally catch up with Russell, who has raced ahead with Oliver Reed and a bevy of tall blonde models who are practicing their archery skills.</p>
<div id="attachment_1934" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/models-archery-10001.jpg"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1934" class="size-full wp-image-1934" title="models archery 1000" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/models-archery-10001.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="484" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1934" class="wp-caption-text">Martyre de Saint Sébastien à la Ken Russell</p></div>
<p>“<em>Z Cars</em> it ain’t,” says Westbury.</p>
<p>I set up a shot. Russell checks it and seems happy. Then, out of the blue, Westbury turns to me and says, “Would you like to operate?” I leap at the chance. “Yes, yes, please, thank you.”</p>
<p><strong>CULTURE SHOCK</strong><br />
A few months ago I was making films for Australian station TCN9. I had a wind-up clockwork 16mm Bolex camera and a crew of none. Today I’m shooting 35mm film using cameras I have never used before. I have two film assistants and four grips to help—and there must be 50 or more models, actors and technicians here.</p>
<p><strong>THIS CLAPPER IS NOT FOR BURNING<br />
</strong>The last night at Eastbourne is a big candlelit procession with hundreds of extras. I do close-ups on a 75mm and switch to an 18mm wide angle. I am walking backwards at night over wobbly, broken rocks. Maybe this is why Westbury asked me to operate…</p>
<p>We get to a cove with a campfire. Our star, Oliver Reed, is there. His fire is dying.</p>
<p>“More wood, we need more wood!” shouts Russell. “Stefan, I want your clapper!”</p>
<p>“No, Ken. I need it.” <em>“Rubbish, you can make films without a clapper. Give it to me!”</em></p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/public/05Learn-ProdDiary-KenRussell-3_0.jpeg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>“Z Cars it ain’t,” says Westbury.</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>“I can’t! It’s not for burning!” He grabs my clapperboard and tosses it onto the fire.</p>
<p><strong>TWELVE YEARS LATER<br />
</strong>Russell has made <em>Women in Love, The Devils, Mahler, Tommy</em> and many more, while I have built sound and television studio Molinare in London. One Friday night, he arrives to be interviewed. I am waiting at our front door.</p>
<p>“Ken, I’m Stefan. Do you remember me? I was the cameraman on <em>Debussy</em>.”</p>
<p><em>“Of course. You’re the crazy Australian who threw his clapper into the fire.”</em></p>
<p>Russell Harty, the talk show host, appears. Ken disappears with him into the studio. Drat! I never had a chance to set the record straight.</p>
<p><em>“No, Ken, you’re wrong. YOU burned my clapper. You did it, not me!” </em></p>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A FOM CALLED FRED</title>
		<link>/2016/05/03/a-fom-called-fred/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 23:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=1908</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[GOOD NEWS AT THE BRITISH MUSEUM I’m working for ITN, the news station owned collectively by the UK commercial television stations. No, “working” is the wrong word. ITN is a union shop. No fault of mine, but I’m stuck in &#8230; <a href="/2016/05/03/a-fom-called-fred/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>GOOD NEWS AT THE BRITISH MUSEUM</strong></p>
<p>I’m working for ITN, the news station owned collectively by the UK commercial television stations. No, “working” is the wrong word. ITN is a union shop. No fault of mine, but I’m stuck in a dispute between the union and management. I’m not working.After three months of doing nothing, my boss has a solution: he will try to get me a job at the BBC.</p>
<p><em>“Phone me at 4:00 and I’ll give you the news.”</em></p>
<p>I just happen to be at the British Museum. It’s the summer of 1964, at 4 o’clock. Cell phones haven’t been invented yet. No worries, the museum has a pay phone. Just the one. Anxiously, I dial ITN. “John Cotter, please.”</p>
<p><em>“Good news, Stefan. The BBC has a vacancy. It’s not news but film productions. You start on Monday. Go to Ealing Studios and report to your FOM at the White Lodge.”</em></p>
<p>“FOM?”</p>
<p><em>“Film operations manager. No need to come in here again—we’ll post you any back pay and holiday pay. Good luck, bye.” Click. So ends my so-called employment at ITN.</em></p>
<p><strong> MONDAY</strong></p>
<p><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/04Learn-ProdDiary-FOMCalledFred-11.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1914" title="04Learn-ProdDiary-FOMCalledFred-1" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/04Learn-ProdDiary-FOMCalledFred-11.jpg" alt="" width="650" height="488" /></a><br />
I’m at Ealing Studios, famous for its Ealing comedies like The Ladykillers (1955). The White Lodge front door is locked. I find a side entrance.</p>
<p>“Good morning. I’m new, a cameraman. I’m looking for my FOM.”<br />
<span style="text-align: center;"><br />
“<em>Up the stairs, second desk on the right. His name is Fred.”</em></span></p>
<p>There he is: my FOM, Fred.</p>
<p><em>“You don’t know how lucky you are. See that pile of envelopes? They are all job applications. Hundreds of them—and we have just ten holiday relief vacancies. Well, nine, now that you’re here.”<br />
</em><br />
“I’m a holiday relief cameraman?”</p>
<p><em> “You’re employed for three months just to cover the summer holiday period. Didn’t you know? Sorry, they should have told you. When our guys come back from holidays, we let people like you go. Sounds tough, but it will be a good experience. You can add BBC to your CV.”<br />
</em><br />
I spend the day with Fred. The BBC canteen is nearby and huge. Fred introduces me to everyone: cameramen, editors, electricians. I really like Fred. I love the buzz.</p>
<p><strong>FRED LIKES ME, HE REALLY LIKES ME<br />
</strong><em>“Here’s the deal, Stefan. I will move you around. You’ll work on documentaries, TV serials, and if anything sensationally good comes up, I’ll put you on it. That’s a promise.”</em></p>
<p>One day Fred calls me into his office: <em>“You have a month to go on your contract. I’m putting on a 90-minute feature to be directed by Ken Russell. He’s shooting on 35mm. Big-name actors like Oliver Reed &#8230;”<br />
</em></p>
<div id="attachment_1917" style="width: 660px" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/04Learn-ProdDiary-FOMCalledFred-22.png"><img aria-describedby="caption-attachment-1917" class="size-full wp-image-1917" title="04Learn-ProdDiary-FOMCalledFred-2" src="https://stefansargent.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/04Learn-ProdDiary-FOMCalledFred-22.png" alt="" width="650" height="481" /></a><p id="caption-attachment-1917" class="wp-caption-text">Director Ken Russell, left of frame, in my nighttime Debussy shoot. Actor Vladek Sheybal on the right.</p></div>
<p>Oliver Reed I know, but I’ve never heard of Russell.</p>
<p><em> “You know, he directed Mahler. You must have seen it. I’ve paired you with Ken Westbury—he’s one of our best cameramen. Oh, you’ll need a BBC estate car. Here’s a pickup slip. Go to the BBC garage in Hammersmith and collect.”<br />
</em><br />
My dream come true. A few months ago I was in Australia shooting on a wind-up 16mm Bolex and now I’m shooting a feature in 35mm. And I have my own car.</p>
<p>Little did I know that Ken Russell would go on to make classic features: <em>Women in Love, Sons and Lovers, The Devils.<br />
</em><br />
And little did I know that one night, he would burn my clapper.</p>
<p style="text-align: right;">to be continued …</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>SHIBUI IS A STAR</title>
		<link>/2016/03/18/shibui-is-a-star/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Stefan Sargent]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2016 23:25:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[2016]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Production Diary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://stefansargent.com/?p=1902</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[and a right PITA as well Shibui My artisan wife, Tricia, has made a quilt out of linen scraps. She brings it home. “I should have filmed you making it.” “I can make another with a different design. Film that.” &#8230; <a href="/2016/03/18/shibui-is-a-star/">Continue reading <span class="meta-nav">&#8594;</span></a>]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="skip-link">and a right PITA as well</div>
<div>
<div id="block-system-main">
<div>
<div>
<div>
<div><img title="Shibui" src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/public/styles/blog_content/public/03Learn-ProdDiary-Shibui-1.jpg?itok=B8JdaHLW" alt="" width="740" height="560" /></div>
<div>Shibui</div>
<p>My artisan wife, Tricia, has made a quilt out of linen scraps. She brings it home.</p>
<p>“I should have filmed you making it.”</p>
<p><em>“I can make another with a different design. Film that.”</em></p>
<p>“Great, but let’s hang this one up as a background. You do a piece to camera and give me some VO. The sun is out, we should do it now.” I grab my <a href="https://pro.sony.com/bbsc/ssr/micro-xdcam/cat-broadcastcameras/product-PXWX70/">Sony PXW-X70</a>, plug the HDMI output into a very old Sony LMD-2020 20-inch LCD monitor.</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="right">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/public/03Learn-ProdDiary-Shibui-2.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>X70 wide shot of big quilt</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Shibui, our Himalayan puss and would-be film star, pricks up her ears and leaps onto the table at the edge of the frame. How does she know just where to be? She preens and prances around in the only corner that is in the shot. Talk about upstaging.</p>
<p>Tricia does her thing, but she is struggling with the coconut remains of a seven wonder bar in her mouth. I stop shooting.</p>
<p>Tricia goes to the bathroom for a thorough tooth clean and water rinse. Shibui loses interest and wanders off.</p>
<p>“No, puss, that was only take one. Mummy, with a mouth full of coconut, looked like Francis the Talking Mule. We have to shoot it again.”</p>
<p><strong>Take Two</strong></p>
<p>“First positions, please!” This is where you need a team of production assistants and cat wranglers. It was not to be—Shibui leaps off the table and comes around to watch Tricia on the 20-inch Sony monitor. Everyone wants to be a director.</p>
<p>The next day I’m at Tricia’s workrooms. I use the Sony HXR-NX30U for my handheld shots. Amazing image stabilization, a great wide Zeiss lens and excellent audio. Just leave the thing on auto-everything and it all comes out. For me, the choice between this little lightweight camera and the ubiquitous Canon EOS 5D is a no-brainer.</p>
<table border="0" cellspacing="1" cellpadding="1" align="left">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td><img src="http://www.creativeplanetnetwork.com/sites/default/files/public/03Learn-ProdDiary-Shibui-3%20copy.jpg" alt="" /></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td>NX30 shot of Tricia choosing squares for smaller quilt</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>Sony, in its wisdom, has discontinued the NX30, but you can pick one up secondhand for less than $1,500.</p>
<p>For interviews, I use the Sony PXW-X70. Why? Because it has a 1-inch sensor that lets me throw the background out of focus, and on <a href="http://www.bhphotovideo.com/c/product/1072752-REG/sony_pxw_x70_professional_xdcam_compact.html">B&amp;H</a> it’s under $2K. It records 10-bit color at 50 Mb/s, but who needs that for a routine YouTube video?</p>
<p><strong>Editing</strong></p>
<p>OK, I know I’m odd, but I transfer in real time using a <a href="https://www.blackmagicdesign.com/products/decklink">Blackmagic DeckLink HD Extreme 3D</a> card.</p>
<p>Shibui sees me editing. In a flash she is in front of the FCP monitor and stomping all over my<a href="http://www.logickeyboard.com/shop/frontpage.html">Logickeyboard</a>. I lift her off the table. Whoosh! She’s back again.</p>
<p>“Puss, darling, Daddy is working. Get lost or no more Fancy Feast.”</p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
